{
    "id": "5949e9d6039d46de923f6485a729d584",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The baby takes …………………….. her mother.",
            "description": "Take after = resemble",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "for",
                "after"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6e6ae88c7d704db69cad852a5526708b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The minister was forced to take his controversial remarks …………………….",
            "description": "To take something back is to withdraw a statement.",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "down",
                "back"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d580d86b8b004b948d35f1e73a44e723"
        },
        {
            "question": "Be careful. He might try to take you ………………………",
            "description": "To take somebody in is to cheat them.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "on",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9fe6a2831e8044ee9e76c97e92e47921"
        },
        {
            "question": "This blouse is loose for me. I must take it ……………………….",
            "description": "To take something in is to make a garment tighter.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "in",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "917fb6c5fd2440baacb2a28c301a297e"
        },
        {
            "question": "She was not capable of taking her children ……………………… hand",
            "description": "To take somebody in hand is to control them.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "72c04d5242204bc2b98f8034410a70b5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The plane is about to take …………………….. Please wear your seat belts.",
            "description": "When a plane takes off, it becomes airborne.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "on",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9454d305559a44b2ade7f5b9973a3015"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must take your shoes ……………………… before entering the temple.",
            "description": "To take a piece of clothing off is to remove it.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "on",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "90600090dbe244fd893919d6d295cc02"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody was willing to take ………………………… the responsibility.",
            "description": "To take on is to accept.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "over",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9e35c2490e2045f0943c2def07c1cf97"
        },
        {
            "question": "I know you had a bad day at work, but you can’t take it ……………………….. on me.",
            "description": "To take it out on somebody is to relieve your frustration by treating someone badly.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "over",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4bc7737edc504066ae0d111fa1f1ca6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Profits of the firm increased after she took ……………….. as the CEO.",
            "description": "To take over is to assume control of something.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "up",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0291a23a9ffb4249990405270cce5487"
        },
        {
            "question": "The children took ……………………… their new teacher immediately.",
            "description": "To take to somebody is to start to like them.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "on",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d8a371f7328f4f36ba0dbb66fe3cb0df"
        },
        {
            "question": "He quit his corporate job to take …………………….. farming.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bcb18e2731a14d7d9b4e35e3df425c38"
        }
    ]
}